A Guide to the Office of the Vice President and Provost Administrative Files, 1984-1997
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Office of the Vice President and Provost Administrative Files 1984-1997
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-3/1/2.991
This collection consists of 5400 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred by Krista English, Office of the Provost, Madison Hall 314, University of Virginia on 1999 July 26.
Scope and Content Information
Office administrative files (correspondence, memoranda and reports) of the Vice-president and Provost including alphabetical topical, office administrative, and miscellaneous files.
Organization
Series I: Topical Files. Boxes 1-6
Series II: Biennial Planning Files. Boxes 7-10
Series III: School Files. Boxes 11-14
Series IV: Restricted Files. Box 15
Contents List
- I: Topical Files
  - Academic Computing Advisory Committee 1992 (Box 1)
  - Academic Enhancement Program 1989-1998 (Box 1)
  - Accountability Reporting 1994 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Application 1997 (Box 1)
  - Admissions Office 1995 (Box 1)
  - African-American Affairs 1987-1994 (Box 1)
  - Alumni 1989-1991 (Box 1)
  - Arabian Peninsula and Gulf Studies Program (APAG) 1994 (Box 1)
  - Arts Dollars 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - Association of American Universities (AAU) 1993 (Box 1)
  - Audit 1992-1994 (Box 1)
  - Barrett Collection 1990 (Box 1)
  - Bayly Art Museum 1987-1991 (Box 1)
  - Benefits 1990-1994 (Box 1)
  - Blandy Farm 1988 (Box 1)
  - Board of Visitors 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Brown College 1992-1994 (Box 2)
  - Callaloo 1992 (Box 2)
  - Capital Reserve 1994 (Box 2)
  - Carr's Hill 1989 (Box 2)
  - Cash Deficits 1993 (Box 2)
  - Center for Innovative Technology (CIT) 1990-1992 (Box 2)
  - Center for Liberal Arts 1988-2000 (Box 2)
  - Center for Public Service 1987-1993 (Box 2)
  - Center for Public Service Search 1996 (Box 2)
  - Chair Establishments and Chair Holder 1986-1993 (Box 2)
  - Classroom Improvement 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - Clinch Valley College 1991 (Box 2)
  - Common Table Lunch 1992-1994 (Box 2)
  - Conflict of Interest 1992-1994 (Box 2)
  - Council for the Arts 1991-1993 (Box 2)
  - Cross-Disciplinary Research 1994 (Box 2)
  - Debt for Scholarship 1991 (Box 2)
  - Decanal Restructuring 1992-1994 (Box 2)
  - Decentralization 1992 (Box 2)
  - Development Office 1990-1993 (Box 2)
  - Downing College Visiting Fellowship 1989-1994 (Box 3)
  - Dual Employment 1989 (Box 3)
  - Earmarking 1991 (Box 3)
  - Office of Equal Opportunity/Affirmative Action (OEO/AA) 1989-1993 (Box 3)
  - Emeritus 1991-1993 (Box 3)
  - Eminent Scholars 1988-1994 (Box 3)
  - Endowments and Awards 1991 (Box 3)
  - Enrollment 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - Enrollment-Dual 1992 (Box 3)
  - Enrollment-Growth Issues 1988-1994 (Box 3)
  - Enrollment-Health and Safety 1990-1993 (Box 3)
  - Evaluations and Operations 1993 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Awards 1990-1994 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Forms 1990 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Salary 1994 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Senate 1989-1992 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Teaching Load 1990-1994 (Box 3)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships 1989-1994 (Box 3)
  - Film Festival 1992 (Box 3)
  - Financial Aid 1989-1992 (Box 3)
  - General Faculty Council 1991 (Box 3)
  - Graduate Teaching Assistant 1990-1992 (Box 3)
  - Handicapped Concerns 1990 (Box 3)
  - Health Sciences 1994 (Box 3)
  - Hereford College 1991-1994 (Box 3)
  - Holland Scholars 1993-1994 (Box 4)
  - Incentive Retirement 1993 (Box 4)
  - Indirect 1984-1994 (Box 4)
  - Information Technology and Communication (ITC) 1984-1992 (Box 4)
  - Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities 1993-1994 (Box 4)
  - Institutional Assessment and Studies (IAS) 1993 (Box 4)
  - International Studies-General 1991-1993 (Box 4)
  - International Studies-Jena 1990-1994 (Box 4)
  - International Studies-Miscellaneous Programs 1990-1992 (Box 4)
  - International Studies-Regent's College 1989-1990 (Box 4)
  - International Studies-Trinity 1995 (Box 4)
  - International Studies-Yarmouk 1990-1991 (Box 4)
  - Jefferson's 250th Birthday 1992-1995 (Box 4)
  - Library 1992-1994 (Box 4)
  - Learning and Education Center 1990-1994 (Box 4)
  - Mountain Lake Biological Station 1991-1993 (Box 4)
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) 1991-1992 (Box 4)
  - Naval Reserve Officers Training Corps (NROTC) 1990 (Box 4)
  - Papers of James Madison 1992 (Box 4)
  - Planning and Development for the Arts 1992-1993 (Box 4)
  - Policy-Smoking 1989 (Box 4)
  - Promotion and Tenure 1987-1994 (Box 4)
  - Provost 1992 (Box 4)
  - Provost Employee Council 1992 (Box 4)
  - Racial Awareness 1990-1991 (Box 4)
  - Registrar 1990-1991 (Box 4)
  - Restructuring 1992 (Box 4)
  - Sexual Harassment 1992 (Box 4)
  - Sexual Relations 1993 (Box 4)
  - Shannon Center 1991-1994 (Box 4)
  - South African Education Program 1991-1992 (Box 4)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools (SACS) 1994 (Box 4)
  - Space Allocation 1991-1994 (Box 6)
  - Student Academic Report 1992-1993 (Box 6)
  - Student Academic Support 1989-1992 (Box 6)
  - Summer Grants Committee 1992 (Box 6)
  - Summer Session 1988-1994 (Box 6)
  - Teaching and Research 1990 (Box 6)
  - Tuition 1990-1993 (Box 6)
  - University Press 1993-1994 (Box 6)
  - University Assessment Program-Activities Report 1989-1991 (Box 6)
  - Upward Bound 1990-1993 (Box 6)
  - University Concerns 1986-1996 (Box 6)
  - University Research Policy Advisory Committee (URPAC) 1993 (Box 6)
  - Vice Provost for Research 1989-1992 (Box 6)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Engineering 1991-1993 (Box 6)
  - Virginia Foundation for the Humanities 1991 (Box 6)
  - Virginia High School League 1982-1986 (Box 6)
  - Virginia Marine Science Consortium 1989-1994 (Box 6)
  - Virginia Museum of Natural History 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - White Burkett Miller Center 1992 (Box 6)
  - Women's Center 1990-1993 (Box 6)
  - Women's Concerns 1989-1991 (Box 6)
  - Woodson Institute 1992-1994 (Box 6)
- II: Biennial Planning Files
  - Budget-General 1990-1994 (Box 7)
  - Budget Addenda 1994-1995, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Budget Addenda 1990-1991 (Box 7)
  - Arts and Sciences Budget 1988-1990 (Box 7)
  - Biennial Budget 1986-1994 (Box 7)
  - Biennial Planning (1-2 of 9) 1990-1994 (Box 7)
  - Biennial Planning (3-7 of 9) 1990-1994 (Box 8)
  - Biennial Planning (8-9 of 9) 1990-1994 (Box 9)
  - Biennial Reports/Contingency Plans 1990-1992 (Box 9)
  - Capital Campaign 1991-1993 (Box 9)
  - Capital Outlay Budget 1984-1994, (3 folders) (Box 9)
  - Capital Outlay Bookkeeping 1988-1998 (Box 9)
  - Cash Deficit 1991-1992 (Box 10)
  - Furlough Plan 1991 (Box 10)
  - Indirect Costs 1989-1991 (Box 10)
  - North Grounds Planning 1988-1990 (Box 10)
  - South Lawn Project 1988-1990 (Box 10)
  - Operating Budget 1988-1993, (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Overbudget Conditions 1988 (Box 10)
  - Budget Reductions 1989-1993, (3 folders) (Box 10)
  - Salary 1994-1995 (Box 10)
  - Faculty Salary-Overload 1990 (Box 10)
  - Faculty Salary Restoration 1992 (Box 10)
  - Tuition Proposal 1992-1993 (Box 10)
  - Year-End Budget 1993-1994 (Box 10)
- III: School Files
  - Arts and Sciences 1985-1994 (Box 11)
  - Arts and Sciences-Anthropology 1990-1994 (Box 11)
  - Arts and Sciences-Art 1993-1994 (Box 11)
  - Arts and Sciences-Asian and Middle Eastern Languages and Cultures 1990-1993 (Box 11)
  - Arts and Sciences-Biology 1989-1993 (Box 11)
  - Arts and Sciences-Chemistry 1988-1994 (Box 11)
  - Arts and Sciences-Classics 1987-1994 (Box 11)
  - Arts and Sciences-Drama 1988-1994 (Box 11)
  - Arts and Sciences-Economics 1990-1994 (Box 11)
  - Arts and Sciences-English 1988-1994 (Box 11)
  - Arts and Sciences-Environmental Science 1991-1994 (Box 11)
  - Arts and Sciences-French 1991-1994 (Box 11)
  - Arts and Sciences-Government and Foreign Affairs 1990-1994 (Box 11)
  - Arts and Sciences-History 1990-1993 (Box 12)
  - Arts and Sciences-Mathematics 1991-1992 (Box 12)
  - Arts and Sciences-Music 1989-1992 (Box 12)
  - Arts and Sciences-Philosophy 1992 (Box 12)
  - Arts and Sciences-Physics 1988-1994 (Box 12)
  - Arts and Sciences-Psychology 1988-1994 (Box 12)
  - Arts and Sciences-Religious Studies 1994 (Box 12)
  - Arts and Sciences-Rhetoric and Communication Studies 1992-1993 (Box 12)
  - Arts and Sciences-Russian and East European Studies 1990-1992 (Box 12)
  - Arts and Sciences-Slavic Languages and Literatures 1994 (Box 12)
  - Arts and Sciences-Sociology 1993 (Box 12)
  - Arts and Sciences-Spanish, Italian, and Portuguese 1994 (Box 12)
  - Arts and Sciences-Division of Statistics 1992 (Box 12)
  - Arts and Sciences-Dean 1986-2000 (Box 12)
  - Arts and Sciences Graduate School 1988-1990 (Box 12)
  - School of Architecture 1988-1994 (Box 12)
  - Division of Continuing Education 1988-1994 (Box 13)
  - Division of Continuing Education-Lynchburg 1990 (Box 13)
  - Division of Continuing Education-Northern Virginia 1990-1994 (Box 13)
  - McIntire School of Commerce 1988-2000 (Box 13)
  - Darden 1987-1994 (Box 13)
  - Curry School of Education 1988-1994 (Box 13)
  - School of Engineering and Applied Science 1989-1994, (3 folders) (Box 14)
  - Law School Building 1992-1994 (Box 14)
  - School of Law 1988-1995, (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - School of Medicine 1992 (Box 14)
  - School of Nursing 1988-1992 (Box 14)
- IV: Restricted Files (Box 15)